[narrator]
Previously on
"The Mentalist.."
You know what Red John's
trying to do, don't you?
He asked me
if I'm ready to quit.
- How does Jane seem to you?
- I think he's in trouble.
You tortured the guy,
for Christ sakes.
I gave an evil psychopath
justice.
I'm not gonna apologize.
You're fired.
Get outta here right now.
Don't do anything rash.
We can work this out.
We'll fix it.
Idoubt that.
Let me help you.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
Hey, Sammy.
Hey.
- Thank you.
- There you go.
[glass clatters]
[exhales sharply]
Magic, huh?
"Magic?"
Tough business.
Yeah. No,
uh, I'm-I'm..
...I'm not
a magician, no.
- No?
- No.
You do coin tricks
and you have the look.
What is the look?
Like you're hiding stuff.
I've seen you around..
Served you drinks
a couple times.
Yeah, I remember.
Uh, Lorelei, right?
How you doing?
I'm-I'm Patrick.
Hey, Patrick.
So you're not a magician?
No. No,
I'm a con man.
I steal from people.
Ah, wow!
You just come
right out and say it.
"I steal from people"
like, "I sell shoes"
like, it's not
a big deal.
Well, it's not
If you know
what you're doing
it's very easy.
Well, it's a big deal
because it's wrong
to steal from people.
No such thing as wrong.
Really?
When did that happen?
Well, there's
legal or illegal.
There's, uh...happy or sad.
Rich or poor,
alive or...dead.
But there's
no wrong or right.
Stuff just happens,
that's all.
One damn thing
after another.
Of course,there's wrong or right.
You know that.
I killed a man last year.
Turns out he wasn't
the man I wanted to kill.
Wrong guy. Anyway..
..now when I recall
shooting him dead..
...still feels good.
It's a happy
little memory to cherish..
...like Christmas.
Now you're just trying
to shock me, aren't you?
- Yes.
- Mm-hmm.
You seem
like a happy soul, Lorelei.
- You happy?
- Yes. I am.
- Well, that's nice.
- Mm-hmm.
What's your secret?
- Faith.
- Oh...yes.
Yes, I've heard that.
[chuckles]
Patrick.
This is nice.
Been looking for you.
How you doing?
Everything okay?
Well, how you doing, Oscar?
I'm good.
How you doing?
Good. This is,
um, Lorelei.
Lorelei? What are
you guys drinking?
Uh, same again
for my friends here.
Cognac for me.
This is an amazing man
right here.
Mm.
This man can reach beyond
the veil of death.
- Did you know that?
- Uh, no.
No, we-we just met, really.
You ever lose someone?
I lost my mother
when I was five.
[clears throat]
But this man..
...he let me
talk to her.
And I truly felt
her presence.
She said
she loves me.
She's always
watching over me.
Wow.
Well, it's both a gift..
...and a curse.
Yeah, well..
[slurps]
...I told my father
all about you.
[Oscar]
'About, uh, what an awesome'
'spiritual experience it was.'
Mm-hmm.
Best ten grand
I ever spent.
My father,
he's a tight bastard.
He says, "ten grand?
"Screw that bitch.
Go get your money back."
Turns out
my mother's not dead.
She ran off with
her aerobics instructor.
She lives
in San Juan, Puerto Rico.
'Owns a nail salon.'
That explains why she was
so easy to contact, I guess.
[chuckles]
[laughs]
That's good
you can smile about this.
- Here's the thing--
- 'I'm gonna be forgiving.'
Give me my money back..
...and, uh, Mervin
here is gonna tune you up
a little, that's all.
You, uh..
...you mind if I, um..
Give me
my money back.
Yeah, um, can I?
Pass a light. Thanks.
Um, I don't have it.
I spent it all.
Okay.
Well, Mervin's
gonna break
your arms
and the legs..
...and then when
you're walking again..
...you'll owe me 50 grand.
- Ah!
- C'mon, let me.
I got it,
I got it, I got it.
Go get him.
[dramatic music]
[tires screeching]
[car horn honks]
[dramatic music]
There he is.
[music continues]
[foot steps]
Ah!
[giggles]
[Oscar]
'Where you going?'
[grunting]
[car siren waling]
[groaning]
[Oscar]
'Merv!'
[man #2]
Police, hold it
right there!
Alright, alright.
Stay where you are.
[man #3]
'Oscar stay. Don't move.'
You all right?
[grunting]
[taser crackling]
[instrumental music]
[Rigsby]
So Benjamin does this thing now
where he kinda
scoots forward
on his butt
like a penguin.
- It's so cute, it's insane.
- Yeah.
Oh, wait. I got a clip on my
phone. Let me find it for you.
- Hey, T.
- Hey, Pat.
[Pat]
How you doin'? Guys.
- Hi.
[Lisbon]
Oh, God.
What did that?
Shotgun, from about
six inches away.
John Doe all the way.
No wallet, no tattoos
no jewelry, no face.
There's a lot of blood.
He must've been killed
right here.
Robbery?
Well, there's
no foot traffic.
Nothing but offices
around here. It's dead at night.
Well, he must've arrived here
in some kind of vehicle.
There's an interstate ramp
a block away from here.
Our friend could've
come from Oregon.
Give us 20 minutes with him,
and you can bag him.
No hurry.
Hey...sorry about
Jane, by the way.
That's too bad.
Too bad about what?
That he got arrested.
I heard it from
some guys in vice.
He got busted
for assault, fraud..
...narcotics
and resisting arrest..
...in Vegas.
That's terrible.
We should do something.
- Like what?
- I don't know.
Try and talk
to him, I guess.
See if he needs help.
It's been six months
since he left.
Maybe he's changed.
- No.
- 'But--'
I offered him
all the help in the world
and he turned me
down many times.
He has to want to change.
He has to hit
bottom and know it.
That's recovery
101, right?
I guess.
Well, maybe this is bottom.
It's pretty low, boss.
When he wants help,
he'll ask us.
He knows where we are.
- Hey, Pat. Good seeing you.
- You too.
Get our John Doe
here on ice quick.
I think he's gonna be
around for a while.
[Pat]
'Alright, see you.'
[instrumental music[
[keys jangling]
[door lock buzzing]
- Sign that.
- Um.
Ah.
Uh, wh-why am I
being released?
I didn't raise bail.
Somebody raised it for you.
Who was that?
I don't have
that information.
Teresa Lisbon is my guess.
Huh? Lisbon?
I don't have
that information.
Okay. You don't have
You can keep that.
Thank you.
[sniffles]
[sighs]
Oy!
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[sighs]
[instrumental music]
Boss.
Good news, bad news.
Bad news,
our John Doe's prints
didn't get a match,
so we still have no ID.
Of course.
Good news, Sac PD
caught a homicide
on Pacoima and third
last night.
Suspect got away,
but they have an eyewitness
and they recovered
the murder weapon.
A sawed-off shotgun.
Ejected cartridge was
the same make as ours
and Pacoima and third
is only ten blocks
from our murder scene.
That's news,
good news would be
better than that.
- It's a lead.
- You're right.
Sac PD, you said?
Uh, who's the detective
on that?
Not sure. Somebody on
Captain Rupert's night shift.
You're right,
It's a good lead
and I need to get
out of here.
Let's go down in person
and see what they have.
[knock on door]
[instrumental music]
Mm.
Hey.
Surprise.
Yeah.
Lorrie, right?
Lorelei.
Sorry.
This was a mistake.
No, no, no. Lorelei.
I'm very happy
to see you.
Just, uh, been
a little slow today.
It's...it's been
a rough week.
Yeah, I can imagine.
I...brought you
some chicken soup.
For me?
Yeah.
Come in.
Excuse the mess.
How did you know
my address?
The bail bondsman
gave it to me.
How did you know
who the bail bondsman was?
[chuckles]
What are you,
Columbo here
with the third degree?
I'm sorry.
Just a little curious.
I knew who he was,
because...I was the one
that put up the money
for your bail.
That's a lot of money.
I'll-I'll pay you back
as soon as I can.
Figured you were
good for it.
Why'd you
do that for me?
[inhales deeply]
You seemed like
a good man who lost his way.
I could help,
so I did.
And at this point
a straight up
"thank you" would be okay.
Thank you.
There's, uh...a lot
of good men out there..
...who have lost their way.
Wow. You're gonna
make me say it out loud?
[chuckles]
I felt like
we got along pretty good.
there was some kind of..
[gasps]
...weird connection
there between us.
I trusted my feelings.
Damn it. Was I wrong?
No.
You weren't wrong.
Okay then.
I have to
warn you, Lorelei.
Um, I'm not
the great catch
you might think
I am from..
...first impressions.
That's okay.
Neither am I.
Bean, tell these people
what you saw.
I'm collecting
cans on third.
Right next to the park
where they sell their drugs.
There's a gunshot. Boom!
Then a tall,
young, Latin gentleman
come running
out of the park
holding
a sawed-off shotgun.
He trips and falls over.
[chuckles]
Drops the gun.
Then he gets up
and runs away..
...leaves the gun,
and that's what I saw.
The tall, young,
Latin gentleman..
...did you get
a good look at him?
Come right by me.
Got a scar
on his face right here.
- Little chin beard.
- Mm-hmm.
Big gold earring
like a pirate.
Black t-shirt, jeans..
...white shoes.
Anything on the t-shirt?
Logo? Numbers?
- Don't think so.
- Thanks, Bean.
Wait. Close your eyes
and picture him.
Now imagine
him coming toward you.
Oh!
There's a little dog
right here on his shirt.
Not a cute dog.
Like, you know
a snarling dog.
Like a bulldog or a wolf?
Wolf!
Grape Street lobos
wear black shirts
with a wolf on 'em.
- Thank you, Miss Bean.
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, so it's kind
of thin but my guys
will check out the lobos
and we'll let you know.
[Van Pelt]
Well, we can check 'em out
for you, if you'd like.
CBI gang unit has
a really good database.
That's okay, girls.
Thanks, but we
don't even know
if it's the same
gun as yours.
It probably isn't.
Yeah, okay, Rupe.
It was good seeing you.
Yeah.
Talk to the gang unit.
See what they know
about the lobos.
Okay.
I'm gonna take
some personal time.
You take the car.
I'm gonna walk.
Walk?
I mean...okay.
See you.
[instrumental music]
[man on TV]
'The zebra's kick
savesits life.'
Oh. She got away.
'But a neck bite
finally subdues her prey.'
[gasps]
- Mm.
- You okay?
'Brings several months
supply of regular meals.'
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[sizzling]
[instrumental music]
Good morning.
[chuckles]
Good morning,
sleepy lover.
Mm.
You must have
slept 12 hours.
Yeah, I think I was tired.
Mm-hmm.
I gotta go to work.
I made some eggs.
How did you know
I love eggs?
[sniffles]
This is delicious.
Thank you.
We had fun, huh?
Yeah.
Perhaps we can see
each other again.
That's not up to me.
Oh, you have no say in it?
None at all.
He's very restful.
I don't follow you.
I do what Red John
tells me to do.
What?
Your freedom..
...our night together.
That was a gift from him.
You can hurt me,
if you'd like.
No, I don't want
to hurt you.
I've given up.
He knows that.
What does
he want from me?
He doesn't want
anything from you.
After all these years..
...he's come
to see you as an..
...old comrade
rather than an enemy.
He hopes you'll come
to feel the same way.
A comrade.
Patrick..
...look at yourself.
You need a new life.
He can give
that to you.
You have to leave.
He's offering
the hand of friendship.
If you refuse him,
he'll be upset.
- Anyone would be.
- Get out.
You know
where to find me.
[instrumental music]
Hey, Grace,
you seen Lisbon?
She had to take
some personal time.
Where'd she go?
Didn't say.
We have a lead.
I just got this
from the gang unit.
Kevin Cintron,
aka Purple.
Affiliated with
the Grape Street Lobos.
Matches the witness
description exactly.
Did you show
the witness the photo?
I do that,
and we have to go through
Sac PD Homicide
and they'll wanna
take the bust
and we need the bust.
Must be a thousand bad guys
with gold earrings,
beards and scars.
I got an address
from his PO.
After killing two people that's
probably not where he's at.
It's a good place to start,
though, and I'm going.
You want me to get you
some doughnuts while I'm out?
[bell chiming]
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
[Patrick]
'This is God.'
'What is it now?'
[laughing]
You scared
the life out of me.
[exhales sharply]
I crawled
all the way on my
hands and knees
from that door.
- But it was worth it.
- What are you doing here?
It's good to see you.
How have you been?
Worried sick
is how I've been
and then you pop in here
like some sort of a lunatic
playing games,
asking me how I've been.
- Just--
- Shame on you.
Stay calm, okay?
It's important that
no one sees us together.
[sighs]
Why not?
I'm faking my breakdown.
It's a ruse
to trap Red John.
You son of a bitch.
You...son of a bitch.
Okay, we are in a church.
Uh, wait, so how does
faking a breakdown
if that's what
you're reallydoing
because it looks
pretty real to me
how does that
trap Red John?
What does
Red John want from me?
What did he send
that little girl to ask me?
- Do you give up?
- Exactly, and I do give up.
I quit. I burn
the Red John files.
I freak out
at the boss.
I admit defeat,
and I sink
into a terrible
depression.
Brilliant.
You did that part great.
Now what?
And why doesn't
he just kill me?
Because it's too easy.
He wants to turn me.
He wants to make
me his disciple.
So I admit defeat,
and then he reaches out
to start a conversation.
That's all
supposition.
- He's not gonna--
- He already has reached out.
He sent me
a message.
I need to
start a new life
and he can help me.
Help you?
He wants to help you?
- Yeah.
- What are you gonna do?
Well, I'm gonna
take him up on the offer.
I'm in a lot
of real trouble.
I do need
a new life.
Yes, you do.
That's what makes
the gag work.
- Then what?
- Well, I don't know.
I let him lead.
That's the beauty of it.
He thinks I'm the fish
and he's the fisherman.
Unless he sees the truth.
I am giving him
his heart's desire.
He will see
what he wants to see.
Or not.
Fooled you.
I can fool him.
Yeah, you fooled me
all right. Well done.
Yeah.
Well..
...I'm sorry.
I tried calling.
I...tried calling you
hundreds...of times.
Begging you
to talk to me.
to get help.
Not a reply.
Not a word.
Not a text.
Sorry.
You know what?
I have not
been sleeping.
I've been...forget it.
Never mind.
You know,
y-you're a jerk.
And your plan?
It's stupid.
It's not even a plan.
But you will help me?
What am I
supposed to say, no?
God, you're despicable.
Take this.
It's clean.
I'll call you on it
when the time comes.
In the meantime,
do not contact me.
Do not let anyone
from CBI contact me.
And don't tell
anyone the truth.
Not a soul.
I cannot believe
you didn't tell me
you were doing this,
that you couldn't trust me
with a secret like that.
We're supposed
to be partners.
God knows,
I am happy you're back.
It is a huge relief.
But what you did..
...frankly, was a betrayal.
God, I hate you, Jane.
I hate you!
We have your prints
on the shotgun, Kevin.
We have an eyewitness
who saw you shoot
Dashawn Willits
with that shotgun.
I'm showing them
the gun because
I'm trying to
sell it to 'em.
Fool tried to take
the gun from me.
I had no other choice.
But the first
shooting, though.
The white John Doe
on Lincoln Avenue.
Did that guy try to
steal your gun, too?
I didn't touch
that man, all right?
He killed himself.
I swear to god.
Me and my boy, Manfreddo
we cruisin' down
the alleyway, we lookin' for
open windows,
to be honest with you.
I see this guy sittin'
up against the dumpster.
Got a bicycle next to him
and a sawed-off shotgun.
Just as we start
to get close...
Damn if he don't
blow off his head.
Hara-kiri.
No messing around.
How do we know
you're telling the truth?
You don't.
You just know what is.
Come on, man,
you guys ask Manfreddo.
He gonna tell
you the same thing.
Yeah. Man just shot himself.
Boom! Freaked me out.
I wanted the gun,
but Kevin took it.
I got the bike.
Sweet fixie.
Where's the bike,
Manfreddo?
Got stolen.
I know.
Ironic, right?
Did you take
anything else from him?
We looked.
He had nothing on him.
I think he's telling
the truth, Cintron admitted
to the second
killing no problem.
Why would he
lie about this one?
Looks like
we'll never know who he was.
- Poor soul.
- Mm.
Lisbon, a word?
Yeah.
Uh, is that the John Doe
case you're working on?
Yes, sir. It looks
to be a suicide.
Oh, good. Excellent.
Get that off the books, eh?
Um...I wanted
to talk to you about Jane.
It's been six months
since he's gone.
I think it's time
for a little outreach.
Well, it's the humane
thing to do.
He was a big part
of the CBI family, after all.
I suppose, but--
I jus-I...I just wanna
give him a call, see if..
...you know, I can't
persuade him into rehab
or a psychiatry
program or some such.
You know, it could
make a big difference
in his sentencing.
He could get
community service.
He could come back
and work for us eventually.
God knows...we need him.
Closure rates being what
they are right now...low.
Yes, sir, and we will
do our bestto fix that
but I don't think
we can help Jane.
Besides, yeah,
he's made his bed.
I don't...think
I could work with him again.
I need someone
I can rely on.
I'm surprised.
I thought you
would wanna help him.
Well, I do.
It's not how it looks.
I just have a feeling
Jane's better off
left alone right now.
Okay.
It was just a thought.
[instrumental music]
I've been, um,
I've been thinking about
what you said
about your friend.
Yes.
You said that
he could help me
start a new life.
- Right?
- Mm-hmm.
What does
that mean exactly?
A new identity...money.
A place to live.
A job, if you want one.
And I-I do what
in exchange?
Accept his friendship.
- It's that easy?
- Sure.
He-he'll wanna
speak to you first.
Make sure
you're on the level.
If that's all right.
Yeah.
And you'll need
to bring him a gift..
...to show your
respect for him.
What kind of gift?
Well..
...Teresa Lisbon's
dead body
would be
the perfect thing.
[laughing]
That's absurd.
[instrumental music]
What did
you tell me?
There is no
right or wrong.
There's just stuff
that happens.
No, no, there-there
has to be something else.
[sighs]
I can't think
of anything else
that would
please him.
Well, I can't do that.
I understand
you're not there yet.
But look at it
from his point of view.
How else will he know
you've trulyhad
a change of heart?
[dramatic music]
[elevator bell dings]
- Jane.
- Not now.
Alright, I'm glad
to see that..
[music continues]
[Van Pelt]
'Jane.'
Jane.
Well.
It's good
to see you all.
How are you?
Uh, we're good.
Never better.
Jane?
There you are.
[ominous music]
Good luck, Teresa.
[cocks gun]
Love you.
[gunfire]
[dramatic music]
[crying]
What happened?
- What happened?
- Patrick Jane.
[Cho]
'He took Lisbon.'
Is he...oh,
oh, my God!
Uff, his face, who..
...who-who is th-who is that?
It's Rigsby.
[Cho]
'It's Wayne Rigsby.'
[crying]
Check, move forward, contain.
Turn it up.
[woman on TV]
'In a macabre twist,
after killing Agent Rigsby.'
34-year-old
father of a baby boy
the suspect, Patrick Jane
took Agent Teresa Lisbon
'presumed dead,
away with him'
when he escaped.
Authorities
will not speculate
as to why he wants
her dead body.
Oh. I'm hungry.
I'm going
to the store for nachos.
You guys want anything?
They got pizza, hot dogs.
I'm good.
Me, too. Uh, Rigsby.
[Rigsby]
'Yeah, I know, I know.'
Don't call Sarah. I know.
It's killing me, though.
She must be
freaking out.
Well, look
at the bright side.
Think of how happy
she's gonna be
when you come
back to life.
Huh.
So where'd you
find this place?
The owner
owes me poker money
he'll never pay back.
Oh.
So that thing you said
before you shot me.
Uh, what did you mean?
What did I say?
- I was kinda hyped up.
- Oh, boy. Me, too.
I thought at any moment
we were gonna get found out.
Mm.
[cell phone ringing]
It's her.
Hello?
Spoke to my friend.
He wants to meet with you.
2369 Foxglove Parkway..
...Southwest, Las Vegas.
Go there at 3:00 today
and wait for instructions.
2369 Foxglove
Parkway, at 3:00.
Don't forget the gift.
I have it right here.
Don't bring
the whole thing.
Just the head.
Okay.
[inhales deeply]
So you want the good news
or the bad news first?
You lost
two fine agents.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
I knew Jane
was wrong somehow
but I certainly
never expected this.
Well, nobody did.
We received
no evaluation
that indicated
danger of this sort.
CBI is in no way liable.
Hm.
Well, the question remains.
Why did Jane do this?
Orders from Red John?
If so, why now?
Why Lisbon?
I was talking with Lisbon.
I suggested we...reach out
to try and help Jane
because he was
in trouble and she said "no."
Very firmly.
She said,
"it's not how it looks."
Meaning what?
I don't know.
I don't know
what to think.
[Lisbon]
'Pretty much
the whole neighborhood'
'is in foreclosure.'
'There's hardly anyone there.'
'It's like a ghost town.'
Smart move
by Red John.
Tough to set up
any kind of
'surveillance in advance.'
Any movement's
gonna be conspicuous.
[Rigsby]
He must be suspicious.
No, he's just cautious.
And he's hooked.
He believes.
How can you be sure?
Because he wants
to believe.
We're doing this thing,
so let's just do it.
Is everybody clear on the plan?
We're gonna move soon.
[Rigsby]
'Yeah.'
Hey, you guys, listen..
...I want to apologize
for deceiving you.
Whatever.
And thank you
for...helping me now.
- We're helping the boss.
- Yeah. She's helping you.
We're helping her.
Guys, cut him some slack.
Oh. Yay, team.
[instrumental music]
[engine turns over]
[tires screeching]
A 12. Rigsby W.
[rattling]
[exhales sharply]
No face.
Right.
Could be anybody.
Well, this's
"Rigsby" here.
No mistake.
Do you have
a tape measure?
Sure.
[keypad beeping]
Bill, I need you
to find out ASAP
where Kimball Cho
and Grace Van Pelt are located.
Yeah, right now.
Hold on one second.
Put that
at the top of his head.
5'11".
This isn't Wayne Rigsby.
Yeah. Find out
where they are.
Thanks. And, Bill?
I want arrest warrants
prepped for every single member
of that CBI team,
dead or alive.
[ominous music]
[music continues]
Mm-hm.
The game begins.
[rattling over the radio]
[rattling]
[Patrick over the radio]
'Hey, Lisbon.'
Must have been
a while since you rode on
the handlebars
of a man's bike.
[Lisbon over the radio]
'Ha ha.'
Well, it's kind of romantic.
Wind in your hair.
You're a sick man.
5-0-5-9.
5-0-6-5. 5-0-6..
Uh, there is no 5-0-7-1.
There's nothing.
It's just desert.
There's no one here.
[engine revving distantly]
Hang on.
Long black limousine.
We're moving in,
we'll be on the scene
in three minutes.
Stay healthy till then.
'Wait.'
Let's just be sure.
[car brakes squealing]
[Patrick]
'Large man with a gun..'
'...Red John's girl.
This is it.'
[dramatic music]
All right,
we're moving in.
[tires squealing]
[tires screeching]
FBI. Turn off the car
and show me your hands.
FBI! Nobody move!
CBI! Don't shoot!
We're CBI agents!
You're making
a terrible mistake.
- Get out.
- Now!
We're in the middle
of an operation.
Put your hands
on the car.
[FBI agent #1]
'Stay where you are
and don't move.'
Hi.
Hey.
That the gift?
- Red John in there?
- Mm-hmm.
He's looking forward
to speaking with you.
You know, Patrick..
...there's
a childish hopefulness
about you that is
really quite adorable.
Put it on the hood.
So what is it,
a football?
A cabbage?
Melon..
...honeydew.
Organic.
Adorable.
Frisk him,
then beat him..
...a little.
[instrumental music]
Uh!
Well, well, well.
- Agent, this is a mistake.
- Agent, you don't understand.
- No, I don't understand.
- Please listen to me.
[Darcy]
'You're supposed to
be dead, as are you.'
This is very strange.
Susan, I am begging you.
Please listen
to what I'm saying.
Our fake deaths
were a ruse to trap
Red John,
and it worked.
Jane is with
him right now,
and his life
is in grave danger.
He's at 5-0-7-1
Keston Avenue.
Uh-huh.
That's enough.
We haven't got much time.
Put him
in the passenger seat.
[grunting]
[breathes sharply]
[breathing heavily]
[Red John]
'Hello, Patrick.'
[ominous music]
Hey.
How you doing?
Debonair
at all costs, huh?
When did
you know?
'Oh, you strung me along'
'for a good long while.'
'Well done.'
Luckily, I have
a good friend in the FBI.
So, I found out
when the FBI found out.
Cat got
your tongue?
I have
nothing to say.
Really?
Nothing?
Uh, "go to hell"
goes without saying.
So, yes,
nothing.
As you
well know, Patrick.
There is no hell.
When I die,
I won't be punished.
What if you really
did have a change of heart?
What if you
and I were friends?
[Red John]
'Imagine the life
we could lead.'
It's a higher path,
Patrick.
A nobler existence.
Like I said,
"go to hell."
As you wish.
Lorelei, cut off
two of his fingers.
'You choose which.'
'Then we should go.'
[grunting]
Uh!
- Ah.
- I'm sorry.
Ah! Ah!
[siren wailing]
[gunfire]
[dramatic music]
[siren wailing]
[tires screeching]
[gun firing]
[gun firing continues]
[instrumental music]
- FBI!
- FBI, turn off the vehicle!
[FBI agent #2]
'Let me see your hands.'
C'mon, outta the car.
Get your hands up.
Turn around,
face the car.
[instrumental music]
[beeping on the speakers]
[woman on the speaker]
'This call
has been disconnected.'
'Please hang up
and try your call again.'
[beeping on the speakers]
Oh, shit!
'This call
has been disconnected.'
Ugh!
Uh!
Ah.
[car door opens]
[car doors closes]
You all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Never better.
[instrumental music]
[siren wailing in distance]
[siren wailing]
[instrumental music]
I'm very happy
to meet you, Lorelei.
We rarely get
the chance to talk
to someone who knows
Red John so well.
Good to meet you, too.
Heard so much about you.
We were lovers,
him and me.
Did he tell you that?
No?
Why not, lover?
[Lorelei]
'You ashamed of me?'
Did we do something bad?
I know it's hard
to believe now
but you're
gonna talk to us.
[Patrick]
'You're gonna break down,
and you're gonna tell us'
everything you know
about Red John.
You're gonna
sing like a bird.
No, lover.
I won't.
Yes, you will.
[instrumental music]
[theme music]
[music continues]